Laura Jamieson: Curriculum Vitae

Software development scholarship graduate with a background in creative design and experience working within a team to deliver full PERN stack web applications from conception to deployment.

Professional strengths include creative problem solving, written and verbal communication and time management. Detail oriented mindset developed from 3 years working within the construction industry.

laura_jamieson@hotmail.com **07714740821**

PROJECTS

Book Face -

A study resource sharing website for academy scholars.

- Automated Discord Posting on resource submission
- Resource filtering by search input and tagcloud
- Test automation with Jest and Cypress

PupVote -

A dog breed voting app

- Using axios to consume APIs
- Used agile working practices and continuous integration to deliver project as part of a team.

PasteBin -

An interactive pastebin website for users to share and store copied texts.

- Like and comments functionality
- Form inputs

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript/ TypeScript

React

HTML/CSS

Express

Node.js

PostgreSQL

Figma

Adobe Indesign & Photoshop

Git Version Control

AutoCad

Revit

EXPERIENCE

Academy, Manchester — Software Engineering Scholar

JANUARY 2022 - CURRENT

- Developed and built user-friendly full stack web applications using JS React, Express.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL using GIT version control and Jest and Cypress end-to-end testing.
- Worked as part of a team to deliver full stack applications using CI/CD and agile practices such as stand-ups, function sprints and code reviews.
- Participated in leadership mentoring to further develop communication skills, focusing on active listening, feedback and technical presentation skills.
- Completed regular pair programming exercises to enhance team working and problem solving skills.

Martin Evans Associates, Sheffield — Graduate Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2020

- Traveled out to sites to undertake surveys, analyzed user needs using communication skills to understand client problems.
- Produced detailed structural calculations for small scale engineering projects.
- Created structural drawings and construction layouts for extensions, new build homes and refurbishment projects.
- Managed personal work schedule to meet and exceed client deadlines.

Jmarchitects, Manchester — Architectural Assistant, Part 1

AUGUST 2017 - MAY 2018

JUNE 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

- Entrusted with the responsibility of representing JMA by leading meetings with clients and consultants.
- Designed proposals for 15 railway station staff areas, including Liverpool Lime Street, Manchester Oxford Road, Manchester Victoria and York Stations which promoted gender equality and religious diversity within the workplace.
- Presented my final designs to the client using publications I had produced to clearly convey the existing problems and my own proposed solutions.

EDUCATION

The University of Sheffield, MArch Architecture (Dissertation with Commendation)

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2021

MA meeting the requirements for RIBA Part 2

The University of Sheffield, Architecture and Engineering (2:1)

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JULY 2017

Dual Course, MEng in Structural Engineering and RIBA Part 1 Architecture. Course accredited by both RIBA, ICE and IStructE

Carmel College, St Helens

2010 - 2012

A levels: Math (A), Biology (A), Physics (B)

Wade Deacon High School, Widnes

2005 - 2010

5 A*and 4 A grade GCSEs including Math, Science and English

ACHIEVEMENTS

Full clean UK driving license

(2021) Dissertation 'Beyond a Binary Cistern' published in SSoA Feminist Library

Designer for the Sheffield Engineering Rugby team crest

Designer for the Sheffield Engineering Society logo

(2014) Publicity Officer for the Architeers Society

(2013) Treasurer of the Architeers Society

Gold Duke of Edinburgh Award

HOBBIES

Passionate rock climber used to staying calm under pressure.

Weekend hiker motivated to meet and overcome new challenges